PAUL SPENCER

Software Engineer & AI Integrator

+31 6 46 395 141

• Amsterdam, The Netherlands

British and Irish (EU)

in linkedin.com/in/spencerpj

spencerpj.com

github.com/McFunshine

Summary

Software engineer with nearly three decades of delivering innovative solutions across fintech, energy, and govtech sectors. For the past half decade, concentrated on AI and emerging technologies, including RAG chatbots, LLM integration, and audio AI solutions. Completed a Master's in Software Engineering in 2022 while maintaining full-time employment. Currently architecting AI solutions with practical business outcomes using OpenAI, Anthropic, Google AI, Groq, Replit, and Fal AI for text, image, and audio processing. Hardworking, adaptable and committed to continuous professional development.

Experience

Khonraad Software Engineering

Lead AI and Emerging Technologies Architect

Amersfoort, The Netherlands Apr 2019 - Present

Technologies: Kotlin, Java, C#, Azure, OpenAI, Kotlin Multiplatform, JetBrains MPS, Python

- Responsible for complete development lifecycle of the innovation projects, including:
 - A RAG chatbot providing guidance across the WvGGZ laws
 - A full-featured iOS and Android App using Kotlin Multiplatform with OpenAI integration
 - OCR integration solutions
 - Domain-specific language extension for Decision Engine using JetBrains MPS

Captain McFunshines Software Engineering

Freelance Software Engineer

Soest, The Netherlands Aug 2019 – Present

Technologies: Kotlin, Azure, AWS, OpenAI, Kotlin Multiplatform, Python

- Developed Podmorph, an AI-powered solution for podcast and radio professionals
- Integrated multiple AI services (Anthropic, Google AI, OpenAI, Groq, Replit, Fal AI) deployed on AWS and Azure

Baker Hughes

JewelEarth Platform Evangelist

Delft, The Netherlands Jan 2014 - Apr 2019

Technologies: C#, SQL Server

- Developer and Product Evangelist of a subsurface modelling platform for the oil industry

Kempen & Co

Senior .Net Developer

Amsterdam, The Netherlands
May 2007 – Dec 2013

Technologies: C#, K2, SQL Server, VBA

- Various internal projects to manage large portfolios and indexing products

Unisys

Developer

alagies VDA WebIntelligence C#

Schiphol Rijk, The Netherlands May 2001 – May 2007

Technologies: VBA, WebIntelligence, C#

- Reporting developer for world wide Accounts Receivables

ACT Financial Systems

London, UK

Developer Nov 1999 – Apr 2001

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe, Visual Basic 6

Developer and supporting Engineer for a stockbroking settlement system

HSBC Investment Bank

London, UK

Developer Feb~1999-Nov~1999

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe

- Developer for message processing, report writing, and screen handling programs

Lloyds Bank Stockbrokers Support / Business Analyst London, UK

May 1997 - Feb 1999

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe, VBA, Visual Basic 4

- Support and Report Developer for internal customers

Education

Universiteit van Amsterdam

Masters Software Engineering

Amsterdam, The Netherlands Graduated 2022

- Thesis: Projecting Rules: Improving Comprehension of Business Rules with Projectional Editing Making the Drools DSL Projectional with MPS
- Relevant Module: Software Evolution Used language workbenches to measure the evolution of a large Java codebase

Note: Completed while maintaining full-time employment

Wolverhampton University

BA European Business Administration

Hogeschool Holland

HEAO Joint European Business Administration

Wolverhampton, U.K. Graduated 1996 Amsterdam, The Netherlands Graduated 1996

Certifications

- $-\ 15$ Microsoft Certifications including 5 MCPDs in Windows, Web and Azure
- $-\,$ Nederlands Als Een Tweede Taal (NT2) Niveau 2

Languages

- **English:** Mother Tongue

- **Dutch:** Fluent spoken, listening and reading, intermediate written